doctorsrepublic.com 2013-04-21

# Online Doctors Community, Doctors Professional Network | Doctors Republic

* * *  
  
We value you as a customer and respect your right to privacy. In the process of operating the Web Site, we may become aware of information relating to you, including information that is of a confidential nature. We are strongly committed to protecting your privacy online and have taken steps to protect such information. This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses the privacy practices for DoctorsRepublic.com. (collectively "Doctors Republic") with regard to your ("You" or "Your") use of the website (www.doctorsrepublic.com) (the "Site" or "Sites"). Doctors Republic is committed to Your privacy. The policy is effective from the date and time a user registers with Doctors Republic by filling up the Registration form and accepting the terms and conditions laid out in the Website user Agreement. Doctors Republic hereby notifies You of the following:   
  
1\. Personally identifiable information collected from You through this Site.  
2\. Process of using the information.  
3\. Information sharing process.  
4\. Procedure of protection of Your information.  
5\. How You can seek to correct any inaccuracies in the information.  
6\. The Doctors Republic contact address for privacy questions.   
  
**THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**  
  
**Information collection**

Doctors Republic is the sole owner of all Your personal information collected on this Site. We will not sell, share, transfer or rent any personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this general statement and the Website User Agreement. Doctors Republic collects information from You on the Profile and Registration pages ("Profile pages") on our Site. Doctors Republic reserves the rights to collect, disseminate, sell or otherwise disclose any non-personal information provided by You.   
  
**Registration**

During the collection of information at the Profile pages on the Site, You are required to give your contact information and other details (such as name, address, birth date, physician license information, medical school, institutional affiliations, e-mail address and the like). An e-mail address and birth date is used to confirm Your identity. An email address is also used to contact You about the materials and information available on the Site. When the Site requests Your identity, the Site will clearly indicate the purpose of the inquiry before the information is requested. All of your professional information will be authenticated against a third party provider.   
  
**Personal Profile**

Once a registered participant, You may provide additional information in Your personal profile describing your credentials, professional experiences, academic background, research work, biography and the like. Your personal profile shall be available for viewing by other registered participants of Doctors Republic and will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. Providing additional information in Your personal profile beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional and and You can alter or remove it at any point of time.  
  
**IP Addresses**

Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol or "IP" address. When You request a page from any link within the Site, our Web servers automatically recognize Your domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about You other than the IP address from which You have accessed the Site.  
  
**Third Party Email Addresses**

For the purposes of inviting and introducing third parties to Doctors Republic, You will be given the option to import or otherwise provide email addresses of third parties to Doctors Republic. On so doing, Doctors Republic will not store your username or affiliated password nor solicit or spam any third party email addresses so provided.  
  
**Opt Out Procedures**

Upon initial communication from Doctors Republic, You will be given the option to opt-out of receiving further communications from Doctors Republic. To be completely removed from the Doctors Republic mailing list, You may contact customerservice@doctorsrepublic.com. If You are using an e-mail forwarding service or other similar service please make sure to include the correct e-mail address or addresses.  
  
**HOW THE INFORMATION IS USED**  
  
**Use of Personal Health Information**

Doctors Republic does not collect personal health information about individuals. To submit the personal health details, You must provide and submit information to the Doctors Republic server. Within Your uploaded submission, Doctors Republic does not collect or maintain information that would associate this submission with a specific patient or individual.  
  
**Sale of Assets, Merger, Acquisition, Bankruptcy**

If Doctors Republic becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will ensure the confidentiality of any personal information involved in such transactions and provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.  
  
**Cookies**

We store a cookie on your computer when you visit our Web site. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a users computer for record-keeping purposes. The primary purpose of these cookies is to analyze how users move within our Web site. Use of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the Site. Once You close Your browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on the Site, You would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the Site. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of Your browser. You can reset your Browser to refuse all cookies or allow Your browser to show You when a cookie is being sent. If You reject the cookies on the Site, You may still be able to use the Site, but it shall be limited to certain minimal functionality. The only drawback to this is that the user may be limited in some areas of our Site or limited to certain functions of the Site. Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Doctors Republic only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.  
  
**Log Files**

Doctors Republic may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track Your movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  
  
**HOW INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED**  
  
**Sharing**

Doctors Republic may share aggregated demographic information with Doctors Republic's partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. Doctors Republic shall not be liable for the transfer of any personal identification information resulting from loss or distribution of data, the delineation or corruption of storage media, power failures, natural phenomena, riots, acts of vandalism, sabotage, terrorism or any other event beyond Doctors Republic's control.  
  
**Consulting**

Doctors Republic may partner with another party to provide specific services. When You sign up for these services, Doctors Republic will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. As per Doctors Republic's contractual arrangements with parties, these parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the explicit purpose of providing these services.  
  
**Spam**

Doctors Republic maintains a strict "No-Spam" policy, which means that Doctors Republic does not intend to sell, rent or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third party without Your consent.  
  
**Legal Requests**

Doctors Republic cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties, to enforce laws and third party rights, such as intellectual property rights and laws relating to fraud. Therefore, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, or other activity that may expose us or you to legal liability, Doctors Republic can (and You authorize Doctors Republic to) disclose Your personal data and other information about You as Doctors Republic, in its sole discretion, believes necessary or appropriate.  
  
**Forums Including Discussion Boards, Posts and Blog Comments**

When you participate in a www.doctorsrepublic.com Forum including, but not limited to, Discussion Boards, Posts and Blog Comments, Your name and IP address may be recorded for purposes of maintaining Your own account within the Forums, and preventing abuses of the Forums (see Forum or online community rules for more details). This information is not used to personally identify You outside the Doctors Republic community. In order to diffuse the information in the Site's Forums to a wider audience, Doctors Republic may, from time to time, collect some of Your postings and group them together to use in a specific publication, print, electronic mailing or other public dissemination. At no point however will Your name or IP address be revealed in any publication. In addition, when Your postings are used in this fashion, they may be edited to fit with the general content of the publication being prepared. It is important to remember that whenever You voluntarily disclose personal information in a forum, through e-mail or elsewhere, that information can be collected and used by others. If Your personal information is accessible to the public, You may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of Your personal information. You may participate in any Forums offered through Doctors Republic, but You agree not to post any material the content of which (i) is defamatory, libelous, obscene, indecent, abusive, threatening to others, or in violation of any law; or (ii) infringes the copyright, trademark right, or other intellectual property right of any third party. You will be solely responsible for all content that you post on any Forum of Doctors Republic. You agree to indemnify Doctors Republic and its officers and employees from and against all liabilities, judgments, damages, and costs (including attorney's fees) incurred by any of them which arise out of or are related to the content that you post. Forums are intended only for the personal use of Doctors Republic subscribers, and may not be used for commercial purposes or for organized political activity.  
  
**HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**  
  
**Confidentiality and Security**

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. When Doctors Republic requests that You enter sensitive information, that information is encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software or other security protocol, which encrypts the information you input. No administrator at Doctors Republic will have knowledge of Your password. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to log off from Doctors Republic when finished using a shared computer. Doctors Republic also protects Your personal information off-line. We restrict access to personal information to Doctors Republic employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf and provide services to You. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.   
  
**Links**

The Web Site may contain links to other sites and/or portals on the Internet. While we intend to link only to such sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by such other sites. Please be aware that websites that have links from our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. If You decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to this Site, You do this entirely at Your own risk This privacy statement does not cover the information and disclosure practices of those web sites. When you leave our site, please read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.  
  
**CORRECTING INACCURACIES**  
  
**Correction/Updating Personal Information**

If Your personally identifiable information changes (such as address), or if You no longer desire to use this Site, You can update Your profile on the Profile pages of the Site. Doctors Republic will endeavor to correct, update or remove Your personal data provided to Doctors Republic. When you use Doctors Republic, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes.  
  
**Notification of Changes**

If Doctors Republic decides to change the Privacy Policy for this Site, Doctors Republic will post those changes on www.doctorsrepublic.com so You are always aware of what information Doctors Republic collects, how Doctors Republic uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, Doctors Republic discloses it. If at any point Doctors Republic decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, Doctors Republic will notify users by way of an e-mail. If You have provided personally identifiable information before the changes in Doctors Republic's Privacy Policy, You will have a choice as to whether or not Doctors Republic uses Your information in this different manner. If You choose that Doctors Republic not use Your personally identifiable information in accordance with the new privacy policy, Doctors Republic will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was originally collected.  
  
**Site and Service Updates**

As necessary, Doctors Republic may send You Site and service announcement updates. You are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the Site. Doctors Republic communicates via e-mail with You to provide requested services and to resolve issues relating to Your accounts.  
  
**Consent to This Policy**

The Website User Agreement Agreement is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.  
  
**WHAT IS THE DOCTORS REPUBLIC'S CONTACT ADDRESS FOR PRIVACY QUESTIONS**  
  
Should You have questions about this policy or Doctors Republic's information collection, use and disclosure practices, You may contact us at the address http://www.doctorsrepublic.com/contact-form.php. We will use reasonable efforts to respond promptly to requests, questions or concerns You may have regarding our use of personal information about You. Except where required by law, Doctors Republic cannot ensure a response to questions or comments regarding topics unrelated to this policy or Doctors Republic's privacy practices.
